<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hello! on Javier Tamayo-Leiva</title>
    <link>https://tamayoleivaj.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hello! on Javier Tamayo-Leiva</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://tamayoleivaj.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://tamayoleivaj.com/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tamayoleivaj.com/contact/</guid>
      <description>Do you need help with some analysis or visualization in a professional way? Then let&amp;rsquo;s get in touch, fill out the following fields and I will contact you as soon as possible.
Greetings and thanks for visiting!
Your Name Email Address An email address is required.  Message   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From data loading to visualization in R (easily)</title>
      <link>https://tamayoleivaj.com/post/20220120-dataviz-shortcut/20220120-dataviz-shortcut/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tamayoleivaj.com/post/20220120-dataviz-shortcut/20220120-dataviz-shortcut/</guid>
      <description>Table of Content  Introduction Bring your data to R {datapasta}  How does {datapasta} work?  Plot your data with {ggplot2}  Basic plot  Components of a plot in {ggplot2}  Set Colors
 Choose the graphic with the geom objects Final Plot    Introduction Many times the reason people approach the R language is because they have seen that it is a great tool for achieving better visualizations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello #TidyTuesday</title>
      <link>https://tamayoleivaj.com/post/20211123-hello-tidytuesday/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tamayoleivaj.com/post/20211123-hello-tidytuesday/</guid>
      <description>Since I started learning R, my main motivation has been to get amazing visualizations like the ones made by Cédric Scherer, Georgios Karamanis, and Thomas Lin Pedersen among many others. What mesmerizes me about them is that to achieve them you have to deal with code, data handling and proper graphical selection, but also understand about aesthetic design in order to achieve a great piece of visualization. However, while some are more trained and/or have been gifted with skills and taste for design and aesthetics - if there is something alike - for me it has been a journey in both aspects of data visualization, becoming enjoyable wingmen of the data science journey.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello Blog!</title>
      <link>https://tamayoleivaj.com/post/20211123-hello-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tamayoleivaj.com/post/20211123-hello-blog/</guid>
      <description>Since I realized all the possibilities about coding in R -mostly- but also in other language, I wanted to create a blog to share some of the things I have learned. However, I also like the idea of a blog as a platform to share incoming knowledge as a learning-teaching process. So now, at the end of my PhD, seems to be the right time and opportunity to do so, while creating a portfolio of the things and skills I have picked up in the process.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
