<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>DataViz on Javier Tamayo-Leiva</title>
    <link>https://tamayoleivaj.com/tags/dataviz/</link>
    <description>Recent content in DataViz on Javier Tamayo-Leiva</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://tamayoleivaj.com/tags/dataviz/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Descriptive statistics and visualization in R</title>
      <link>https://tamayoleivaj.com/post/20220624-dataviz_descstat-shortcut/20220624-dataviz_descstat-shortcut/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tamayoleivaj.com/post/20220624-dataviz_descstat-shortcut/20220624-dataviz_descstat-shortcut/</guid>
      <description>Table of Content  Introduction Loading your data in R  How to load the data from RStudio?  Descriptive statistics with {stat} in R  Central tendency measures Dispersion measures Distribution measures Variance analysis  Plot your data with {ggplot2}  Basic plot  Components of a plot in {ggplot2}  Choosing Colors Choose the graphic with the geom objects  Complete your analysis with {ggpubr}  {ggpubr} functions  Final plot   Introduction Many times I have seen that people are interested in learning R because of the visualizations that can be generated with packages like {ggplot2}.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From data loading to visualization in R (easily)</title>
      <link>https://tamayoleivaj.com/post/20220120-dataviz-shortcut/20220120-dataviz-shortcut/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tamayoleivaj.com/post/20220120-dataviz-shortcut/20220120-dataviz-shortcut/</guid>
      <description>Table of Content  Introduction Bring your data to R {datapasta}  How does {datapasta} work?  Plot your data with {ggplot2}  Basic plot  Components of a plot in {ggplot2}  Set Colors
 Choose the graphic with the geom objects Final Plot    Introduction Many times the reason people approach the R language is because they have seen that it is a great tool for achieving better visualizations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello #TidyTuesday</title>
      <link>https://tamayoleivaj.com/post/20211123-hello-tidytuesday/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tamayoleivaj.com/post/20211123-hello-tidytuesday/</guid>
      <description>Since I started learning R, my main motivation has been to get amazing visualizations like the ones made by Cédric Scherer, Georgios Karamanis, and Thomas Lin Pedersen among many others. What mesmerizes me about them is that to achieve them you have to deal with code, data handling and proper graphical selection, but also understand about aesthetic design in order to achieve a great piece of visualization. However, while some are more trained and/or have been gifted with skills and taste for design and aesthetics - if there is something alike - for me it has been a journey in both aspects of data visualization, becoming enjoyable wingmen of the data science journey.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
